It still hasn't come.
Could this be what you're looking for by any chance?
Rei, Kiriyama.
The day has finally come for us to play against each other in public.
This letter just arrived for me in the mail, so I figured that you would be receiving one as well.
That's why I decided to come right over.
Be it right or wrong, I just felt like I had to deliver it to you with my own hands.
So, you opened my mailbox?
Do you realize that that's illegal?
I've been waiting for this.
It's true that it did take me two years longer to reach 4th Den, but this is now our true start.
Let the true battle between us begin.
You even opened the envelope! That's a crime, I hope you know!
Ever since the first day I played against you at the National Children's Shogi Championship 10 years ago,
I decided you would be my lifelong rival, and every day I have strived to make steady progress.
I've researched in the moonlight, read by the light of the fireflies,
and convinced myself that I was simply born a late bloomer.
However, the truth is I'm a genius too.
Hey!
Wait!
You bastard!
I was still talking!
I know, but it was done listening, alright?
No, not until you take it from my hand!
This notification is a declaration of war!
Never mind, I'll call the association for the information myself!
Don't be so cold to a buddy!
We're best friends, remember?
Best friends?
This is the first I've heard of that!
Where'd you get that idea?
Isn't that the way it always goes?
We strive, we have our rivalry, and we overcome our challenges!
And in the end, high five!
We become best friends forever!
Got it?
Come on, go with the flow!
In boys' manga, these are standard rules!
Yeah, well, the main character of an average boys' manga
wouldn't just show up with a smug expression
and then try to steal somebody else's mail.
Anyway, where's Mr. Hanaoka?
He's usually with you whenever I see you.
Oh, my servant?
He's on a marvelous vacation right now!
Thank you for being a wonderful friend to the young master!
In appreciation of his 45 years of service to our family,
we've given him an all-paid 80-day cruise around the world!
Ta-da!
Yep!
Mr. Harunobu, please take good care of yourself!
I shall be home again soon!
I can't thank you again!
80 days all along?
That means Nikaida will be on the loose the whole time!
So, I've been thinking about our upcoming game.
Will you go with a one-turn-loss-bishop exchange?
That is, if I go first!
Or will you try using a side pawn capture instead?
I suppose I could tell you.
But if I did, how would you know if it was really the truth?
Oh, come on!
Don't be so uptight about it!
Once we start, your strategy will be obvious anyway!
Then why not just keep your eyes peeled on that day
and find out for yourself?
I'm preparing!
You know, I'm getting mentally psyched up for it!
Why would I want to help you get mentally prepared against me?
This is all kinds of wrong!
Kiriyama, these are delicious!
I give up!
Help me, Mr. Hanaoka!
No!
Oh!
Oh, oh!
Oh, yeah!
It's not an oops!
enorme invest, but like it is the guest.
Oh, yeah, thanks.
Oh, no!
Oh!
Oh, table!
Oh, no!
Oh, yes!
I like the river. There aren't many things that I really like, but watching the way the river flows is almost hypnotic. It really helps to ease my mind. It's only one subway stop to Sendagaya, but on my game days, I like to look at the river on the way, so I walk to the nearest train station.
I end up crossing several bridges. It's strangely soothing, maybe because I lived in a town surrounded by water when I was a kid. Although, my memories of that time are faint now.
A professional shogi player has 30 to 40 matches a year. There are title matches and rank deciding competitions, mostly held in tournaments. So the more you win, the more matches you end up playing.
There are even some top class players who have 70 to 80 matches a year. Today's match is a qualifier for the NHK Cup. It's an important match. If I can make it past the qualifying round this time, then I'll be able to participate in the final televised tournament.
And as you can guess, it'll be broadcast to the whole country.
I pray that I can win this match and be on TV. Please help me beat my opponent Rei Kiriyama with my own shogi technique. Help me incinerate his amoeba-like by-the-book play with my burning manly soul.
I pray that I can win this match.
Did I just catch you running away? You know what that's called, don't you? It's called a spiritual defeat.
His name is Isa Matsumoto. Class C2, 26 years old, 5th den. He plays very aggressively. In fact, all he really does is attack. He charges at his opponent like a ball of fire.
I can't see.
What the hell? Scary.
I can see it now!
Do you mind? Knock it off, Isa. We're trying to concentrate.
Sorry about that, Smith. I guess I kinda got a little carried away there.
Well, you do always wear your heart on your sleeve. But still, knock it off. You're distracting me from mentally keeping track of all my pieces.
This is Smith. Class B2, 6th den. It seems they get along well because they're both tall.
How do you like them apples, Kiriyama?
Hey.
What? What was that? Wait! Whoa! You're putting a pot over there? Huh? What? No way! If I take it, his horse will move back!
Yohohhoh!
Yeah!
It's not over just yet.
No, I still have a chance. It's not over.
Oh, no, he didn't. It can't be over yet.
Hooray.
Huh?
He wanted his granddad in the country to see him.
Unfortunately, the old man's ill in the hospital.
But he could have watched Isa win on the NHK broadcast.
Isa's grandpa is the one who first taught him how to play Shogi
when he was just a child.
Hey, cheer up, Isa!
Ha! Kyoyama's treating with his winnings!
Don't you want to see Akari?
Huh? Sweet Akari?
Akari!
Why do I have to treat? No fair!
Of course it is! What's a kid gonna do with all that money?
I'm underage, so I can't buy you any drinks.
You may not be able to have any liquor, but you can have some soft drinks!
We have to cheer up Isa! Or he'll cast a dark cloud over the whole Shogi hall.
Well, hello!
Good evening, Mr. Matsumoto. It's nice to see you again.
Hi, Miss Akari! Long time no see!
Hello there! You look just as beautiful as ever.
Please, have a seat.
Sure. Of course!
She's a totally different person here.
She's nothing like this at home.
Maybe... she really is a different person.
Here! Fresh orange juice for you, right, Rei?
Yeah, thanks.
Hey, Rei! Thanks for helping us with the gift boxes the other day.
No, I was wrong. She's definitely the same person. Women are fascinating.
Much better! Now I'm feeling good! I'm gonna keep drinking!
It's Aunt Kiriyama! Hope you're ready! With your wallet!
Yahoo!
You're a lucky boy, Rei. How nice to spend the evening with such fun friends.
Even if you aren't drinking tonight, they're as bubbly as champagne.
I hope you realize there's no peer pressure at all. I'd never force anyone to drink.
But you'd sponge off of me against my will.
You do know how expensive it is to drink in Ginza!
Some players aren't as nice as you. Others might force a boy to drink until he blacks out.
They might even... abandon him in front of a club.
I'm going to drink.
Are you okay? Where are your friends? Did they leave you all alone here?
Have some water. Where do you live?
I... live in Junetown.
Oh, that's my neighborhood. I live nearby in Marchtown.
Can you walk?
I'm going to walk.
can you walk oh no you're just skin and bones i think you weigh even less than i do
when i woke up the next morning i was in their living room
no no just leave him alone he's awake hi um where am i oh good morning
want some miso soup even though it was my first time there i had a nostalgic feeling about the place
it was the first time i met akari's sisters hina and momo they took care of me
these are the kind of people i like to go out with what to go out with they're so kind and reliable
yes that's me all right you know you can count on me for anything right kiriyama bullying young
players sponging off them just because you can how awful you would never find me doing that cheers
drink up kiriyama have as much as you'd like it's on me great good on you isa don't mind if i do hey
hold on i gotta pay for you too here's to isa how about a toast ray cheers
this akari is very different from the akari i know at home but either way i think both of them
of them are very beautiful
julian high vaom
hugin
nothing in here
no instant noodles milk i know
extremely uncomfortable
flour
no toilet paper either
Guess that means I have to go shopping.
Where I live in Junetown, there are only businesses, warehouses, and factories.
The only way to get food and daily essentials is by crossing this bridge
and going to the supermarket on the other side.
I wish there were at least a bento shop nearby.
I hate going to restaurants and street stalls by myself.
Marchtown is on the other side of the bridge.
That's the town where Akari and her sisters live.
It's so hot. There isn't any shade. I feel like I'm melting.
For some time after moving to this town, no matter where I was walking,
it felt like I was in a dream.
I couldn't hear sounds of the city very well,
and the town seemed to flicker in black and white tones.
But later on I began to realize I was still in shock.
Living alone in a town that I wasn't used to.
But as soon as I started meeting new friends,
it felt like the other side of the bridge lit up in living color before me.
They said to come over any time, but did they really mean it?
Still, just knowing that I have a place I can go to is enough.
And being alone most of the time doesn't seem so lonely anymore.
What's that?
It smells like something's burning.
I can smell smoke.
Fireworks?
It's cool in here.
Oh, that's right.
It's Obon.
I found you, Ray!
Hi, Mama.
Oh, hey, Ray.
Are you out shopping too?
Instant noodles and sweet buns, huh?
I've invited you for dinner, but you never come.
Well, I'm very sad to say that it looks like Ray would rather have instant noodles
instead of our home cooking.
I can't help but be disappointed.
I did my best to make him a yummy rice ball.
Wait, it was really good.
Don't watch it!
Run away, Ray!
Wait, girls!
It's not the way it looks.
I mean, I just...
Here, take these.
What?
There's a limit of three to a customer.
This is what we really came here to buy.
During the summer, we like to make a lot of cold noodle dishes.
This is what we're having tonight.
Do you like fried chicken, Ray?
Um, well, yeah, sure.
Then come over.
We'll have dinner together.
Okay.
For some reason, I just can't say no to Akari.
Try to vomit.
Then you'll feel better.
Oh, boy.
Don't you know how to throw up?
Fine, I'll do it.
But don't bite my fingers.
Open wide now.
There you go.
There, there.
You'll be fine.
She saw exactly how pathetic I was right from the start.
So I can't gloss it over.
Hello there.
Do you still have hemp twigs?
I sure do.
Are you just starting?
The sun's about to set.
Yes, you're right.
The shopping took us longer than I thought.
Let's hurry.
It's even later than I thought it was.
Okay.
Hina, go and get us a baking dish.
And some matches.
Okay.
Oh, it's lit.
No, no.
Don't touch it, Momo.
That's what I could smell.
You could smell it all through town.
These are the horses?
Yes.
They ride these little horses to get back home.
For grandma and your mom.
Huh?
But you don't know about it yet.
It figures.
How would you know?
We've made these every year.
My mother and her mother before her all made them.
It's our family tradition.
So that's what we do, too.
Thank you for starving.
Yummy food.
Hurry up.
Give us a little more than usual.
Where are your parents buried, Ray?
Do you know?
In Nagano.
That's my dad's hometown.
I see.
That's far away.
All right.
Dinner's ready, everyone.
Great.
Then let's eat.
Delicious.
Just the way I like it.
Hina did most of the frying.
Not bad.
The oil burned me right here.
Oh, dear.
That's the problem with hot oil.
Better take care of that.
Go get the ointment.
It's in one of my drawers somewhere.
There's no reminiscing about the past during this dinner.
This family's wounds are too fresh to even go there.
They're not ready yet.
What was it like for me again?
When did I stop crying?
How long did it take for me to pull it together?
It's strange.
I can't even remember.
I've been in a daze.
I've been living in a daze ever since that day.
I couldn't find anything else to do.
Nothing at all.
When it was time to go, Akari gave me some leftover rice and chicken to take home with me.
Be sure to put it in the fridge as soon as you get home.
You can heat it up in the microwave later.
Come back after your match on Monday.
We'd love to see you.
That'll be the last day of Obon, and we'll make more food.
It's nice having company over.
I thought I heard Akari say, it'll be a good distraction.
But her voice was so soft, I can't be sure.
On the way home as I crossed back over the bridge, the wind was strong.
But the leftovers felt warm against my body, almost soothing, like a small animal.
Your old rival is in there waiting for you and he looks so intense!
You're late, Kiriyama. I was getting tired of waiting.
Excuse me, is the AC on?
Compared to that department store roof, this place is a paradise.
Shall we continue?
Last piece of the fried chicken.
One, two, three!
Don't miss the next episode of March Comes In Like a Lion!
We'll see you then!